<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TOR Project</title>
    <link>https://vib5252.github.io/tor-visualization/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TOR Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vib5252.github.io/tor-visualization/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>https://vib5252.github.io/tor-visualization/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vib5252.github.io/tor-visualization/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project started as a sandbox to learn data science algorithms with a passion backed by my years of security research inspecting telemetry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More specifically, it arose from a desire to understand the concept by applying mathematics to tease out underlying patterns. Patterns of expectation, such as &amp;ldquo;The Weak Law of Large Numbers,&amp;rdquo; still blow my mind how this abstract form converges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vib5252.github.io/tor-visualization/posts/process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vib5252.github.io/tor-visualization/posts/process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The TOR public API gives a rich amount of data that is perfect for exploring latent features. This project explores a pipeline for &amp;ldquo;trust&amp;rdquo; scoring of TOR relays using a hybrid of unsupervised learning and a final linear classifier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;unsupervised-process&#34;&gt;Unsupervised Process:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dimensionality Reduction:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Linear&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;PCA (Principal Component Analysis): Projects high-dimensional data onto a lower-dimensional linear subspace (eg: 2D) by preserving maximum variance. Used as an input to t-SNE/UMAP to reduce feature noise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Non-Linear&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;t-SNE (t-distributed Stochastic Neighbor Embedding): Preserves local structure, meaning points close in high-dimensional space stay close in 2D. Lacks global relationship.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;UMAP (Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection): Preserves local and some global structure, making it well-suited for highlighting latent topology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clustering:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vib5252.github.io/tor-visualization/posts/visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vib5252.github.io/tor-visualization/posts/visualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;snaphot-8-3-2025&#34;&gt;Snaphot (8-3-2025)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../plots/Tor_Relays_Clustered_Geographically_by_Features_map.html&#34;&gt;View Map&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;A world map showing Tor relays positioned by geographic coordinates and colored by key behavioral features (such as role flags or bandwidth categories).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This visualization helps connect physical relay distribution to behavioral roles, revealing geographic concentrations of specific types (e.g., Guard-heavy zones or Exit-dense regions). Useful for spotting regional relay patterns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../plots/RBM_Anomaly_Energy_Overlay_UMAP.html&#34;&gt;View RBM Plot&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;A 2D UMAP embedding of Tor relays, colored by RBM energy values representing the model&amp;rsquo;s confidence or reconstruction error for each relay.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Higher energy scores may indicate anomalous or rare behaviors, while lower scores align with well-modeled, typical relays. This plot highlights latent behavioral outliers, useful for surfacing unknown roles or transitions not captured by flags alone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
